Ayodeji Saberedowo

Frontend Web Developer

Detail

Lapaloma Close, Jahi, Abuja. Tel 2348165712071 ayodejisaberedowo@gmail.com https://ayodejisaberedowo.me

Profile

Seasoned and independent Front End Developer with 5 years of experience in blending the art of design with skill of programming to deliver an immersive and engaging user experience through efficient website development, proactive feature optimization, and relentless debugging.

Very passionate about aesthetics and UI design.

Experience

Frontend Developer at Digymedia Ltd.

March 2020 - till date

- Deliver engaging user experience through optimization of images, code, and cross-browser compatibility, increasing Time on Page by +60 seconds for +50 websites
- Expand features, refine code, and improve processes, producing smoother operations and enhancing user engagement
- Designed dynamic and browser compatible pages using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, and Javascript.
- Built single page applications (SPA), responsive web design, UI using HTML5 grid layouts, CSS3 media queries where its an expression and can be used to either true or false.
- Ensure efficient web development by supporting designers and app developers while resolving website performance issues

WordPress Web Developer at Shopmovies Ltd.

Jan 2019 - Dec 2020

- Built responsive websites, blogs and e-commerce sites through WordPress CMS.
- Wrote website copies using SEO keywords drawn from Google Analytics.
- Delivered responsive, cross-browser compatible and accessibility compliant websites, achieving 19% faster load time than industry average
- Produced stunning visual elements of web applications by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code while producing high quality, reusable markup using HTML5 and CSS3

Education

Ladoke Akintola University of Technology Ogbomosho

Sep 2012 - Sep 2018

• B.Tech(Hons.) Electronic and Electrical Engineering

Design & Coding

- JavaScript, jQuery
- Frontend Framework (React)
- Responsive UI Design
- WordPress
- Adobe Photoshop
- Visual Studio